

## J. SKY ZHOU

DATA SCIENTISTE, PHD

jazhou.polytechnique@gmail.com

07-85-49-51-09

Plaiseau 91120

Eligible for Crédit Impôt Recherche (CIR)

Work permit: Carte de Résident de Longue Durée (UE)

Physicist with excellent problem-solving, data analysis, communication, and storytelling skills, who takes pride in applying math, statistics, and computer science to solve real-world business problems.

Vi / Pandas / Scikit-Learn
TensorFlow / Keras

Probability & Statistics

Git / SVN / SQL / LaTex

Linux / MacOS / Windows

Chinese / English / French

Python / Fortran / Bash

Machine / Deep Learning
Jupyter Notebook / PyCharm

## PROJECTS

CumuPy

ARPES Experiment A scientific package written in Python made for numerical simulations of photoemission spectrum (numpy, scipy, matplotlib, and pyFFTW).

Main proposer for the ARPES experiment done in the ADRESS beamline of Swiss Light Source. The aim of this experiment was to verify the predictions from my newly derived theoretical method for computing the photoemission spectra. The teamwork involves collaborations with researchers from different domains and countries.

## **EXPERIENCE**

2018-2020

Sorbonne Université (CNRS Post-doctoral Fellow)

· Applied a machine-learning type approach for scientific computing.

2016-2018

École Polytechnique (CNRS Post-doctoral Fellow)

- $\cdot$  Developed and implemented mathematical methods for bleedingedge numerical simulations, leading to several top-tier peer-reviewed publications.
- Proposed a bleeding-edge experiment to confirm my theoretical predictions, with collaborations of researchers from different domains, and countries.
- · Organized ETSF correlation team meeting at École Polytechnique,

## EDUCATION

2013-2016

- Ph.D. in Theoretical Physics (École Polytechnique)
- · Led multiple joint projects producing several top-tier peer-reviewed publications.
- · Participated 10 international conferences with 7 oral presentations and 3 posters (with one best poster prize).
- · Co-organized the 12th ETSF Young Researchers' Meeting in Paris.

2010-2012

M.Sc. in Biophotonics (École Normale Supérieure de Cachan)

- · Acquired multidisciplinary knowledge on biology, chemistry, and physics.
- · Won the Erasmus Mundus Scholarship (48K euros for a two-year study in Europe).

2005-2009

**B.Sc. in Optoelectronics Engineering** (Harbin Institute of Technology - China)